NURAY AHMADOVA

Azerbaijan, Baku | +994503002169 | nuray.akhmedova@gmail.com

PROFILE

Inventive and determined Process/Chemical Engineer with 2+ years of experience in the field and a bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering (2019, Baku Engineering University). Seeking to use previous experiences and knowledge to further proceed in my career path and consistently deliver results.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

09/2021 to Current

Process Engineer

WORLEY - Baku,

Responsibilities:

- Preparation of PFD;
- Preparation of P&ID with necessary preliminary sizing of all piping, equipment, and representation of all instrumentation for plant monitoring, automation, and protection;
- Preparation of detailed sizing of all process equipment and utility systems, with and without the use of software applications;
- Preparation of process datasheet for all equipment and package systems;
- Determining size and specifications for all safety relief valves with the help of software;
- Process selection and simulation;
- Risk assessment of the given systems;
- Development of technical documentation;

04/2019 to 08/2021

Process Engineer

ENCOTEC - Baku,

Responsibilities:

- Conceptual studies;
- Preparation of PFD;
- Preparation of P&ID with necessary preliminary sizing of all piping, equipment, and representation of all instrumentation for plant monitoring, automation, and protection;
- Preparation of heat and material balance studies with the help of

software;

- Preparation of rough cost economics, including preliminary sizing and important details of equipment;
- Preparation of detailed sizing of all process equipment and utility systems, with and without the use of software applications;
- Preparation of process datasheet for all equipment and package systems;
- Determining size and specifications for all safety relief valves with the help of software;
- Process selection and simulation;
- Risk assessment of the given systems;
- Site surveying;
- Development of technical documentation;
- Training/onboarding of the new personnel.

<u>Involved in the following projects:</u>

- Provision front end engineering design for Chia Surkh Block extension project. (Petoil)
- Provision detailed design for Chia Surkh Block extension project. (Petoil)
- Firewater line replacement project. (BP)
- MEG drain lines corrosion management project. (BP)
- Caisson back-spray elimination project. (BP)
- West/East Azeri CCTV upgrade project. (BP)
- West Chirag Optical Backbone Upgrade project. (BP)
- EOP Flare & Closed Drain Rationalization project. (BP)
- Kazi-Magomed Seismic Fault crossing project. (BP)

EDUCATION

09/2015 - 06/2019

BEng: Chemical Engineering

Baku Engineering University (Qafqaz) – Baku

Main Courses completed:

- Material and Energy Balance;
- Fluid Mechanics;
- Organic Chemistry, Inorganic Chemistry;
- CAD/CAM:
- Heat Transfer:

- Thermodynamics;
- Process Design Principles;
- Chemical Reactions Engineering;
- Separation Processes;
- Mass Transfer;
- Catalytic Processes and etc.

COURSES

• Process Engineering Design, Velocis Solutions

Oct 2018 • Jan 2019

• Process Simulation with Aspen HYSYS, Velocis Solutions

May 2021

SKILLS

- Project Management
- Detailed Design
- Front End Engineering Design
- Engineering Drawing
- Risk Assessment
- Technical Documentation
- Knowledge of MS Office
- AutoCAD

- Aspen HYSYS
- Training and Development
- Design Layouts
- Safety Considerations
- Customer Relations
- Team Collaboration
- Leadership
- Team Management

LANGUAGES

English Advanced Russian Native Azerbaijani Native German Beginner

INTERNSHIPS

• Summer Camp Participant, Schlumberger

Aug 2018

- getting acquainted with the departments existing at Schlumberger in Azerbaijan;
- getting basic knowledge on the services provided by the company;

- getting involved in group activities such as group tasks and team building activities;
- responsible for the final project on "Cyclicity of Oil and Gas Prices and strategies to adapt";
- attending workshops at the Schlumberger bases;
- acquiring hands-on experience at the named workshops, such as assembling, disassembling different Harts of appliances.

• Customer Care Strategy Intern, Bakcell

Jul 2016 • Sep 2016

- responsible for the education of the Customer Service Representatives of the company;
- responsible for translating the educational material from Russian to English;
- worked well independently and on a team to solve problems;
- organized and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITY

Observer Marshal, Azerbaijan F1 Grand Prix

May 2021 • Jun 2021

Mar 2019 • Apr 2019

Mar 2018 • Apr 2018

• President of the Committee, AIESEC in Azerbaijan

Feb 2019 • Jan 2020

- main responsible for a committee of 70 people;
- main responsible for the creation of a 1-year strategy;
- main responsible for a team of Executive Board and their performance;
- main responsible for financial budgeting;
- main responsible for plan fulfillment.

Vice President, Talent Management, AIESEC in Azerbaijan

Feb 2018 • Jan 2019

- main HR responsible for a committee of 50 people;
- responsible for the creation of the educational and development cycle for the members;
- responsible for internal communications strategy;
- responsible for a team of managers and their performance;
- main responsible for recruiting new members twice a year.

• Project Manager, AIESEC in Azerbaijan

Feb 2017 • Jan 2018

- responsible for a team of 4 people;
- main responsible for 2 projects;
- responsible for the customer experience of the exchange participants from 5 different countries.